<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>AntennaPod Blog</title>
        <description>AntennaPod Blog posts</description>
        <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://antennapod.org/assets/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>AntennaPod Blog</title>
        </image>
        <language>en-us</language>

        
        
        <item>
            <title>New website</title>
            <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/11/new-website</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/11/new-website</guid>
            
            <description><![CDATA[
                
                <p>Published by <a href="https://github.com/ByteHamster">ByteHamster</a></p>
                <p>Our old website was basically just a single page, which looked okay but it was not too useful. Its FAQ section was outdated and did not follow the design of the rest of the page. Additionally, the FAQ page was linked nowhere – if you did not know where to look, you did not find it. Links to platforms for contribution (<a href="https://github.com/AntennaPod/AntennaPod/">GitHub</a> for development, <a href="https://www.transifex.com/antennapod/antennapod/">Transifex</a> for translations and the <a href="https://forum.antennapod.org/">forum</a>) were hidden in a small footer menu. The website highlighted a few features but it did not describe how to use them. Additionally, the website was a plain html file, making it rather hard to update. You can find the old website on the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200814004524/https://antennapod.org/">internet archive</a>.</p>

<p>After noticing the awesome redesign of the website of <a href="https://k9mail.app/">K9-Mail</a> (open-source email app), I reached out to the designer of that website, <a href="https://github.com/AnXh3L0">Anxhelo Lushka</a>, asking if we can copy the K9-Mail website for AntennaPod. Anxhelo then offered to create a brand new website, specifically for AntennaPod! You are currently looking at our new website. It has more features, like a <a href="https://antennapod.org/documentation">documentation section</a> and a <a href="https://antennapod.org/blog">blog</a>. Thank you very much to the awesome designer Anxhelo!</p>

            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        
        
        
        
        <item>
            <title>2.0.0 release</title>
            <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/09/2-0-0-release</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/09/2-0-0-release</guid>
            
            <description><![CDATA[
                
                <p>Published by <a href="https://github.com/ByteHamster">ByteHamster</a></p>
                <p>Version 2.0.0 is a big step forward for AntennaPod. We rewrote big parts of the user interface, added tons of new features and fixed bugs.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Brand new user interface (by @ByteHamster)<br />
We got rid of unneccessary icons and unneccessary whitespace. You can now see more podcast episodes on your screen and it looks more tidy. Don’t worry - AntennaPod still has the same feel and the way you interact with the app has not changed. It just looks more polished!</li>
  <li>Support for chapter images (by @ByteHamster)<br />
When loading new episodes of a podcast, AntennaPod now supports displaying chapter images. Just play an episode that supports images, head over to the chapters tab on the player screen and have a look!</li>
  <li>Skip intro and ending per feed (by @tonytamsf)<br />
The option is located in feed settings, which you can get to by pressing the cogwheel icon on the feed page.</li>
  <li>Option to show notifications after episodes have been auto-downloaded (by @shortspider)<br />
This is one step into the direction of our most requested feature: being notified for new episodes.</li>
  <li>Bug fixes and improvements (by @ebraminio, @tonytamsf, @JessieVela, @ByteHamster and more)<br />
We have fixed too many things to list them all. They include things like better support for right-to-left languages or fixes when jumping to positions in an episode.</li>
</ul>

<p>You can see the full, huge list of changes on our development platform, <a href="https://github.com/AntennaPod/AntennaPod/compare/1.8.1...2.0.0">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>As of writing this, version 2.0.0 is rolled out to 100% of the Google Play users. At the same time, the first beta release of version 2.1.0 is rolled out to our beta testers. AntennaPod is developed by volunteers in our free-time. If you like AntennaPod and want to give something back to the community, consider contributing by helping other users in the <a href="https://forum.antennapod.org/">forum</a>, <a href="https://www.transifex.com/antennapod/antennapod/">translating</a> or by <a href="https://github.com/AntennaPod/AntennaPod">writing code</a>.</p>

            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        
        
        <item>
            <title>New icon</title>
            <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/09/new-icon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/09/new-icon</guid>
            
            <description><![CDATA[
                
                <p>Published by <a href="https://github.com/ByteHamster">ByteHamster</a></p>
                <p>To all those who participated in the vote for our new brand: THANK YOU! With a total of <strong>6420</strong> votes we have seen a great interest from our community. We’ll get to all their opinions in more detail later, but first things first:</p>

<p>It is with great pleasure that we can announce <strong>the new AntennaPod app icon and logo by 221pxls!</strong></p>

<p><img width="300" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/new-icon-winner.png" /></p>

<h2 id="the-competition">The competition</h2>

<p>In total, we received 12 proposals. You can find a full list of proposals in a <a href="https://discourse.opensourcedesign.net/t/jobs-new-logo-to-go-with-major-app-update/1809/13">post on Open Source Design</a>. After the call closed we (@keunes and @ByteHamster) reviewed all proposals and provided feedback to the designers. Based on the criteria and requirements set out in the <a href="https://antennapod.org/designbrief">design brief</a>, two proposals were selected for the community vote.</p>

<p>After that, we set up a vote containing the two new proposals that follow the requirements in our design brief best, as well as providing an option to vote for the old design. Voters could give one to five stars for each design, representing an equal number of points.</p>

<div class="md-table">
<table>
<thead><tr><td><b>Alpha</b></td><td><b>Bravo</b></td><td><b>Charlie</b></td></tr></thead>
<tr><td>By MyNameIsTroll</td><td>By <a href="https://www.instagram.com/221pxls/">221pxls</a></td><td>Old</td></tr>
<tr><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/icon-poll-alpha.jpeg" /></td><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/icon-poll-bravo.jpeg" /></td><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/icon-poll-charlie.jpeg" /></td></tr>
<tr><td>21314 total points</td><td><b>23323 total points</b></td><td>21718 total points</td></tr>
</table>
</div>

<h2 id="the-charts">The charts</h2>

<p>The total points listed above gives a straightforward indication of the winner. But we wanted to look into the votes in more detail to better understand how each of the proposals was received.</p>

<p>Apart from the total score we found it interesting to see how many users accept a proposal, even if it’s not their favourite. The plot below shows that 60% of the users generally like proposal <em>bravo</em>, while fewer than 50% like the other proposals.</p>

<p><img width="400" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/icon-poll-ok.png" /></p>

<p>Also noteworthy is that 42 users loved all proposals, giving each a five star rating. On the other side, luckily only four users did not like any of the proposals and gave them all 1 star. The old design (<em>charlie</em>) invoked the most <em>strong opinions</em>, with 4% of the voters awarding the existing design 4 or 5 stars while giving the other proposals only 1 or 2 stars.</p>

<h2 id="differences-per-group">Differences per group</h2>

<p>The survey was shared among different groups: Google Play Beta users, our Twitter followers, a random group of Google Play users, and our F-Droid users. For each of these groups we distributed another link to the poll. Below, you can see the rating distribution across different groups. For each group, the <em>bravo</em> proposal was rated best. You can also see the number of participants form each group.</p>

<p>The poll was open for a bit more than a month. The F-Droid users replied so fast that after 3 days we already had 3328 participants and closed that collector again. For Google Play users, the poll was opened for more than a month to get a more equal distribution between different types of users. The poll was rolled out to 16,000 random users on Google Play, out of which 12,700 installed the update and 1994 voted.</p>

<p><img width="400" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/icon-poll-groups.png" /></p>

<p>You can find additional interesting charts here: <a href="https://antennapod.org/assets/downloads/icon-poll-charts.pdf">icon-poll-charts.pdf</a>. If you want to have a look at the raw, anonymized vote data to create your own charts, you can find it here: <a href="https://antennapod.org/assets/downloads/vote-data-ratings.csv">vote-data-ratings.csv</a>. The R script used to generate above charts is available here: <a href="https://antennapod.org/assets/downloads/icon-poll-charts.R">icon-poll-charts.R</a>.</p>

<h2 id="text-comments-for-an-evening-or-three">Text comments for an evening or three</h2>

<p>We know - it’s been quite a wait for those of you who were looking forward to these vote results. In respect of both our community and the hard work of both designers, we wanted to go through all the comments and relay relevant feedback to the designers. So, over the span of several evenings @keunes and @ByteHamster went through <strong>over 4000 open comments</strong>.</p>

<p>Each comment was tagged with one or more categories. After initial tagging we reviewed the list with categories, and made some adjustments to improve our tags. Unfortunately that took a bit longer than preparing the script for the graphs. But the result are the insightful word clouds below! (You can click on them to view a bigger version. We have used a non-linear scale for the word clouds to ensure that both frequently noted and rarely noted words are readable)</p>

<div class="md-table">
<table>
<thead><tr><td><b>Alpha</b></td><td><b>Bravo</b></td><td><b>Charlie</b></td></tr></thead>
<tr><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/wordcloud-alpha.png" /></td><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/wordcloud-bravo.png" /></td><td><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/wordcloud-charlie.png" /></td></tr>
</table>
</div>

<p>After the comment box for each of the proposals we also asked respondents if they wanted to leave a generic comment. Many of them thanking <a href="https://github.com/AntennaPod/AntennaPod/graphs/contributors">the developers</a> for their good work. Going through all those comments was heart-warming.</p>

<p><img width="200" src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/wordcloud-other.png" /></p>

<p>Let us share a small collection of the many nice comments below. Dear all volunteers, developers, translators – let this speak to you!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You, reading this, good work. Hope your day is as good as you’ve helped make mine all by having a nice functioning app experience</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve never been more excited for a software update before.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thanks for AntennaPod! It’s incredible! You certainly would have reason to feel proud of your accomplishments there! A great example where Free Software excels!</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thanks for making this great software! You provide an essential service to many of us and should sleep well at night knowing you’re positively contributing to our world. Thank you!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Some of the plain-text comments contained support questions or feature requests. Given that we don’t know who sent these comments (it’s a survey, after all) it’s not possible to reply to them, but rest assured that we’re keeping them in the back of our minds. If you did have a support question, feature request or bug report, please create a topic in our <a href="https://forum.antennapod.org">new forum</a> so we can help you :)</p>

<p>If you want to have a look at the tagged comments data (not the actual comments) to create your own charts, you can find it here: <a href="https://antennapod.org/assets/downloads/vote-data-comments-tagged.csv">vote-data-comments-tagged.csv</a>. The R script used to generate above charts is available here: <a href="https://antennapod.org/assets/downloads/comments.R">comments.R</a>.</p>

<h2 id="post-vote-changes">Post-vote changes</h2>

<p>As we wrote in the design brief, we provided important feedback to the designer of the winning proposal based on the open comments, taking the opportunity to tweak the design slightly. The logo presented at the top of the page is the final result of these iterations.</p>

<p>Before we let you enjoy your podcasts, we want to thank again all the designers that replied to call on Open Source Design, and in particular MyNameIsTroll and 221Pixels. We hope that you - our community - are happy with the result of this process and will warmly adopt our new face. We will soon release the official release of version 2.0.0 which will include the updated visuals.</p>

            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting to a new icon</title>
            <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/06/getting-to-a-new-icon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/06/getting-to-a-new-icon</guid>
            
            <description><![CDATA[
                
                <p>Published by <a href="https://github.com/keunes">Keunes</a></p>
                <p>After users <a href="https://github.com/AntennaPod/AntennaPod/issues/1281">requested</a> a new icon for over 5 years, I persuaded main developer ByteHamster that the release of version 2.0.0 is a good time to rework the icon. We therefore developed and published a design brief with requirements for the new icon. You can find the design brief below.</p>

<h1 id="design-brief-antennapod-logo-update">Design brief AntennaPod logo update</h1>

<h2 id="about-antennapod">About AntennaPod</h2>

<p>AntennaPod is a podcast manager and player for Android. Contrary to many of its competitors, it is open source (MIT License), developed and translated by volunteers, gratis <em>and</em> ad-free. It allows users to discover new podcasts, download, stream and manage episodes, and launch playback with personal settings and on a range of different devices. It is translated in 17 languages with more than 90% completion (and even 25 languages with over 60% completion). With over half a million downloads via Google Play, AntennaPod is installed on more than 150,000 actively used devices.</p>

<h2 id="assignment--scope">Assignment &amp; scope</h2>

<p>The app’s current main developer is currently working on AntennaPod version 2, an important update with lots of bug fixes and UI improvements. To honour this major step, we are looking for a <strong>new logo and app icon</strong>. The <strong>goal</strong> of the new design is to help give AntennaPod a <em>modern</em> and <em>professional</em> look, which is in line with the updated UI and speaks to the wider audience (beyond open source and privacy advocates).</p>

<ul>
  <li>The logo will be used on the website and in the app</li>
  <li>The icon will be used for the installed app, in app stores and for social media accounts</li>
  <li>Both the full logo and the icon may also be used in potential future communication materials (including print)</li>
  <li>Secondary assignment is the delivery of <strong>simple colour palette</strong> is also expected, as to ensure future consistency</li>
  <li>Ideas are welcome, but not necessesarily in scope of this assignment, for:
    <ul>
      <li>new promotional visuals (hopefully produced following new logo, to announce v2 of the app)</li>
      <li>design ideas for a new, modern website (hopefully done in the not too distant future)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="design-requirements">Design requirements</h2>

<p>The new work must:</p>

<ul>
  <li>contain the name: “AntennaPod” (only for logo)</li>
  <li>use a libre font (so any contributor can create new comms materials)</li>
  <li>still be recognisable as AntennaPod by existing users, and therefore, must
    <ul>
      <li>have blue as primary or secondary colour (any shade, same as or different from current)</li>
      <li>somehow use the concept of an antenna in the icon</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>come positive &amp; negative version (for on light &amp; dark background)</li>
  <li>adhere to <a href="https://developer.android.com/google-play/resources/icon-design-specifications">Google Play icon design specifications</a> (only for icon)</li>
  <li>also come in super small white-on-transparent version legible in super small size (icon only, for Android’s status bar)</li>
  <li>be deliverd in vector format (preferably svg, as not all an open AI files)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="the-current-logo-icon">The current <del>logo</del> icon</h3>

<p><img src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/designbrief-current.png" alt="Current icon" /></p>

<h3 id="the-competition">The competition</h3>

<p>As you can see below, there’s both some variety and a bunch of same-ish icons. Our aim is to get something unique :-)</p>

<p><img src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/designbrief-competition1.png" alt="competition1" /> <img src="https://antennapod.org/assets/images/blog/2020/designbrief-competition2.png" alt="competition2" /></p>

<h2 id="license">License</h2>

<p>Designs are provided with an unlimited and unrevokable license to the AntennaPod project, allowing its use and future adaptations/iterations. The licensed product (the designs) will be used as the project’s (unregistered) trade mark(s) and used and embedded as such in the project’s products (website, app, etc). (cf <a href="https://google.github.io/opencasebook/trademarks/">Trademarks in Open Source</a>)</p>

<h2 id="feedback-iteration-selection">Feedback, iteration, selection</h2>

<p>Keunes (comms) and ByteHamster (lead developer) are responsible for guiding the process. Keunes will be the contact person for the designer(s).</p>

<p>As a community project, contributing users and others interested will have an important role. To that end, the ‘active community’ will be involved (in a resticted manner, as described below). With ‘active community’, we refer to all beta users of the app (3.4k), those following a GitHub issue on the topic (13+) and those following the project on Twitter (867).</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>First round</strong>. After the call for proposals, one to three are selected by Keunes &amp; ByteHamster. Feedback is provided to selected proposals. New iterations based on the feedback (if any) are expected.</li>
  <li><strong>Second round</strong>. The new iterations (and those that stayed the same) are put up for a vote by the active community. Participants will rate each of the proposals, and optionally provide open comments on their favourite proposal. To make sure the winner is validated as better than the current icon, the current icon will also be included. For the most popular proposal, relevant comments will be filtered and bundled by Keunes and provided to the designer. Based on the feedback (if any), an iteration is welcomed but not required.</li>
</ul>

<p>The community will need to sign in with their Google account to be able to vote, in order to avoid malicious votes. Users without Google account are offered an alternative.</p>

<h2 id="timeline">Timeline</h2>

<p>We’d love to hear from you by Wednesday 24 June if you’re interested to help out (or if you have any questions or comments). <strong>The deadline for the proposals will be Saturday 27 June.</strong> ByteHamster and Keunes will then select proposals &amp; provide feedback by the following Wednesday. After, we’ll have two weeks for iterations (if any) and launching the poll in the Beta version of the app on Thursday 16 July. We then hope to be able to implement our new icon by the end of the month :)</p>

<h2 id="financial-thank-you">Financial thank-you</h2>

<p>As a project without official structure or own funds, proper compensation wont be possible. However, as to support open source designers, Keunes would like to offer € 25 to those selected in the first round, plus € 50 to the selected logo. Designers may also decline the offer, in which case their financial thank-you will be donated to the <a href="https://opencollective.com/opensourcedesign">Open Source Design initiative</a>.</p>

<p>Of course you’d be acknowledged by name on the site and in the app’s ‘About’ section.</p>

<h2 id="interested-contact-us">Interested? Contact us!</h2>

<p>Thank you for considering support to this open source app! Reply to the <a href="https://opensourcedesign.net/jobs/jobs/2020-05-26-new-logo-to-go-with-major-app-update">ad on opensourcedesign.net</a> or get in touch at [email adress removed].</p>

            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        
        
        <item>
            <title>Supporting old Android versions</title>
            <link>https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/05/supporting-old-android-versions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://antennapod.org/blog/2020/05/supporting-old-android-versions</guid>
            
            <description><![CDATA[
                
                <p>Published by <a href="https://github.com/ByteHamster">ByteHamster</a></p>
                <p>Supporting old Android versions is hard. Vendors only publish updates for a limited time and the devices’ software decays while the actual hardware would still work great. To look for new episodes, AntennaPod needs to connect to the servers of podcast publishers. While the servers are upgraded to modern cryptography standards, the old devices lack behind. Especially devices with Android versions older than 5.1 are getting more and more trouble fetching new episodes.</p>

<p>To deal with problems like that, Google published a workaround. While AntennaPod is open-source software, Google’s workaround is not. This is not a problem for Google Play users – they received the workaround in the 1.8.0 update. F-Droid only allows to publish 100% open-source apps. The contributor @Slinger has now developed a workaround for F-Droid users. This workaround makes the app size bigger but it fixes various problems. If you are using F-Droid and are wondering why version 2.0.0 needs more space, here here is the explanation.</p>

<p>You can find a more technical explanation on the <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/2020/05/29/android-updates-and-tls-connections.html">F-Droid blog</a>, which also explores ways to deal with the problem without making the app size bigger.</p>

            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        

    </channel>
</rss>
